{
    "questions": [{
        "questionNumber": 1,
        "questionText": "Retrofitted with stabilizing devices, some of which  its aesthetics, thebridge has been reopened, no longer prone to excessive swaying but not quite thebreathtaking structure it originally was.",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answerOptions": ["impair ", "resist", "improve", "enhance", "restore", "compromise"],
        "correctAnswer": [0, 5],
        "explanationText": "The sentence suggests that the addition of devices to make the bridge more stable hasconsequently lessened its previous aesthetic impact as a \"breathtaking structure.\" Thewords \"restore,\" \"improve,\" and \"enhance\" do not describe the appropriate qualitativedirection of the change caused by the retrofitting as \"impair\" and \"compromise\" do.Though \"resist\" makes some sense when inserted into the blank, it does not produce asentence with the same meaning as either of these.Thus the correct answer is impair (Choice A) and compromise (Choice F).",
        "page_num": 89
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 2,
        "questionText": "Although cosmic objects have struck Earth since the planet's very formation,humanity has only recently become aware of these events: two centuries ago theidea that objects orbiting the Sun could collide with Earth was widely           .",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answerOptions": ["ridiculed ", "doubted", "disseminated", "promulgated", "marginalized", "disbelieved"],
        "correctAnswer": [1,5],
        "explanationText": "The colon introduces an example that explains or demonstrates the former lack ofawareness about cosmic collisions with Earth. Because people were not aware of theexistence of events of this type, the idea of their possibility would not have been\"disseminated\" or \"promulgated.\" Although \"ridiculed\" and \"marginalized\" makesense when inserted into the blank, they do not produce sentences with the samemeaning, which \"doubted\" and \"disbelieved\" do.Thus the correct answer is doubted (Choice B) and disbelieved (Choice F).",
        "page_num": 89
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 3,
        "questionText": "That people  the musical features of birdsongs suggests that despite thevast evolutionary gulf between birds and mammals, songbirds and humans sharesome common auditory perceptual abilities.",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answerOptions": ["mimic ", "recognize", "relish", "are confounded by", "can make out", "are puzzled by"],
        "correctAnswer": [1,4],
        "explanationText": "According to the sentence, some human ability or other suggests that humans share aperceptual ability with songbirds. The words that fill the blank must allow for theexistence of this ability in humans, which \"are confounded by\" and \"are puzzled by\" donot. Although both \"mimic\" and \"relish\" make sense when inserted into the blank, theyeach designate more than just perception, and they both lack another word that wouldcreate a sentence similar in meaning.Thus the correct answer is recognize (Choice B) and can make out (Choice E).",
        "page_num": 90
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 4,
        "questionText": "Torpey's study has turned a seemingly    topic, the passport, into afascinating one by making an original contribution to the sociology of the state.",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answerOptions": ["ironic ", "banal", "provocative", "witty", "insipid", "stimulating"],
        "correctAnswer": [1,4],
        "explanationText": "The adjective \"seemingly\" indicates that the words that fill the blank will contrast with\"fascinating.\" Of the responses, \"banal\" and \"insipid\" are both opposites of \"fascinating,\"and they yield sentences alike in meaning, so they are the correct response. While\"provocative\" and \"stimulating\" are near in meaning, they do not provide any contrast to\"fascinating,\" so they are incorrect. Neither of the other responses has a near synonymamong the choices, nor do they provide any opposition to the characterization of thepassport as a fascinating topic.Thus the correct answer is banal (Choice B) and insipid (Choice E).89",
        "page_num": 90
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 5,
        "questionText": "Britain is attractive to worldwide advertisers because it is  market, so thereis no need to tailor advertisements for different parts of the country.",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "answerOptions": ["a global ", "an uncomplicated", "a vast", "a homogeneous", "a uniform", "an immense"],
        "correctAnswer": [3,4],
        "explanationText": "The sentence describes a country whose different parts share a similarity that does notrequire differential action (tailoring for different parts) by advertisers. The blank mustdesignate this sameness. While the words \"vast\" and \"immense\" produce sentenceswith the same meaning--and \"global\" less so--they all describe size, not similarity.Being \"uncomplicated\" might also attract advertisers, but it suggests a different virtuethan similarity, and there is no other word that produces a sentence with the samemeaning.Thus the correct answer is a homogenous (Choice D) and a uniform (Choice E).For each of Questions 1 to 8, select the two answer choices that, when used tocomplete the sentence, fit the meaning of the sentence as a whole and producecompleted sentences that are alike in meaning.",
        "page_num": 90
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 1,
        "questionText": "The band's long-standing strategy of laying leisurely explorations atop a steadyfunk beat has proven to be surprisingly        : a concert in Cologne from 1972sounds as if it could have taken place today.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["fortuitous ", "foresighted", "prescient", "popular", "serendipitous", "lucrative"],
        "correctAnswer": [1,2],
        "explanationText": "The colon indicates that the second part of the sentence supports the assertion madein the first part. Since this second part emphasizes the modern sound of the 1972 concert,the blank calls for choices that refer to the similarities between the band's 1972 sound andmusic characteristic of more recent times. Both \"foresighted\" and \"prescient\" suggest thatthe band's musical strategy anticipated the trends of the coming decades, so they are thecorrect choice. Of the other responses, \"fortuitous\" and \"serendipitous\" are similar inmeaning, but they do not fit well with the word \"surprisingly,\" nor with the emphasis onthe band's having a long-term strategy. Neither \"popular\" nor \"lucrative\" have a synonymamong the other choices; moreover, they too go beyond the sentence's emphasis on theband's seemingly timeless style.Thus the correct answer is foresighted (Choice B) and prescient (Choice C).",
        "page_num": 91
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 2,
        "questionText": "Factory production made an absence of imperfections so blandly commonplacethat the                           of hand-produced goods were now cherished where they oncemight have been shunned.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["advantages ", "revivals", "benefits", "pretensions", "blemishes", "defects"],
        "correctAnswer": [4,5],
        "explanationText": "The sentence suggests a contrast between the quality of factory-produced goods,marked by an absence of imperfections, with that of hand-produced goods, whichmust possess such imperfections. The words \"blemishes\" and \"defects\" are the only onesthat connote imperfection. While \"advantages\" and \"benefits\" produce sentences withthe same meaning, they neither connote imperfection nor make sense as one wouldnot necessarily shun a product with such positive attributes. The word \"revivals\" alsodoes not connote imperfection, and there is no other word that would produce asentence with the same meaning.Thus the correct answer is blemishes (Choice E) and defects (Choice F).",
        "page_num": 92
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 3,
        "questionText": "Through its state associations, the American Medical Association controlled whocould become a physician and dominated  professions like nursing andoccupational therapy.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["commensurate ", "proportionate", "kindred", "affiliated", "imperative", "voluntary"],
        "correctAnswer": [2,3],
        "explanationText": "The blank calls for words that will describe professions such as nursing and occupationaltherapy as they relate to physicians. These professions are also in the health-care field; theanswer choices \"kindred\" and \"affiliated\" both suggest this close relationship andproduce completed sentences that are similar in meaning. Of the other choices, both\"commensurate\" and \"proportionate\" suggest some sort of comparative measurementbetween the professions mentioned, something unsupported by the rest of the sentence.Neither \"imperative\" nor \"voluntary\" would typically be used to describe \"profession\"nor does either have a word close in meaning among the other choices with which itcould be paired.Thus the correct answer is kindred (Choice C) and affiliated (Choice D).",
        "page_num": 92
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 4,
        "questionText": "In a strong indication of the way the entire party is  the candidate withmoderate credentials, the outspokenly conservative former mayor of a major cityhas promised to raise a substantial amount of money for the candidate's campaign.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["rallying behind ", "incensed over", "undecided about", "mortified over", "embarrassed about", "coalescing around"],
        "correctAnswer": [0,5],
        "explanationText": "The former mayor's promise to raise funds is used as an example of the party's attitudeor actions toward the candidate. Since raising funds is a way of supporting a candidate,the words filling the blank must be positive rather than negative. Only two of thechoices given, \"rallying behind\" and \"coalescing around,\" indicate a positive attitudetoward the candidate; moreover, they also produce similar meanings, so they are thecorrect answer. The other four choices indicate negative or indifferent attitudes towardthe candidate that would not be exemplified by promises of fund-raising.Thus the correct answer is rallying behind (Choice A) and coalescing around(Choice F).",
        "page_num": 93
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 5,
        "questionText": "Mr. Hirsch says he will aim to preserve the foundation's support ofthinkers, individuals who are going against the trends in a field or anacknowledged set of opinions.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["iconoclastic ", "integrative", "doctrinaire", "heterodox", "dogmatic", "synthesizing"],
        "correctAnswer": [0,3],
        "explanationText": "The portion of the sentence following the comma defines the type of thinkers charac-terized by the words that will fill the blank. The challenge posed by this item, then, ismainly one of vocabulary: the answers must be words that describe individuals who goagainst the trends in a field or against a set of opinions. \"Iconoclastic\" and \"heterodox\"mean exactly that, with both words describing people whose opinions run counter toestablished norms. Of the other choices, \"doctrinaire\" and \"dogmatic\" both mean theopposite--adhering to established principles--while \"integrative\" and \"synthesizing\"both refer to a willingness to bring together disparate points of view.Thus the correct answer is iconoclastic (Choice A) and heterodox (Choice D).",
        "page_num": 93
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 6,
        "questionText": "In France cultural subsidies are   : producers of just about any film can getan advance from the government against box-office receipts, even though mostsuch loans are never fully repaid.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["ubiquitous ", "invaluable", "sporadic", "scanty", "questionable", "omnipresent"],
        "correctAnswer": [0,5],
        "explanationText": "The colon signals that the second part of the sentence provides an example of the firstpart, so the blank must characterize the idea that just about any film (as an instance ofsubsidized culture) gets an advance. This rules out \"sporadic\" and \"scanty\" neither ofwhich suggest the pervasiveness of the subsidies. While \"invaluable\" and \"questionable\"may make some sense, they do not produce sentences with the same meaning.Thus the correct answer is ubiquitous (Choice A) and omnipresent (Choice F).",
        "page_num": 94
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 7,
        "questionText": "The problem of avoiding duplicate names--such as for Internet domain names orfor e-mail accounts--is particularly  when the name has to fit into aformat that allows only a finite number of possibilities.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["meager ", "acute", "agreeable", "severe", "beneficial", "productive"],
        "correctAnswer": [1,3],
        "explanationText": "The blank must be filled with a word that describes the challenge of ensuring uniquenames under certain limitations. Since these limitations add to the difficulty of avoidingduplication, the blank must be filled with choices that reflect the arduousness of this task.To characterize the problem as particularly \"acute\" or \"severe\" would do this nicely; bothadjectives indicate the added difficulty of the problem under the circumstancesdescribed, and the pairing renders sentences with similar meanings. None of the otherresponses describe the difficulty of the problem that the rest of the sentence emphasizes.Thus the correct answer is acute (Choice B) and severe (Choice D).",
        "page_num": 94
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 8,
        "questionText": "At nearly 450 pages, the novel is  : the author does not often resist thetemptation to finish off a chapter, section, or even paragraph with someunnecessary flourish.",
        "difficulty": "Medium",
        "answerOptions": ["instructive ", "complex", "prolix", "educational", "long-winded", "explicit"],
        "correctAnswer": [2,4],
        "explanationText": "The words that fill the blank in must convey that the novel is not merely long but alsocontains numerous portions deemed unnecessary. While it may be \"instructive\" and\"educational\" these do not properly describe the novel's length. While \"complex\" and\"explicit\" may correlate with (though not characterize) length, they do not producesentences with the same meaning.Thus the correct answer is prolix (Choice C) and long-winded (Choice E).For each of Questions 1 to 7, select the two answer choices that, when used tocomplete the sentence, fit the meaning of the sentence as a whole and producecompleted sentences that are alike in meaning.",
        "page_num": 95
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 1,
        "questionText": "If researchers can determine exactly what is wrong with people who suffer fromthis condition, they may be able to suggest drug therapies or other treatments thatcould         the effects of the damage.",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answerOptions": ["mitigate ", "exacerbate", "specify", "identify", "ameliorate", "stabilize"],
        "correctAnswer": [0,4],
        "explanationText": "The sentence suggests that more information about a damaging condition will allowresearchers to lessen future negative effects. While \"specify\" and \"identify\" createsentences with approximately the same meaning, the sentence also suggests that theresearchers are seeking to control effects that are already known rather than needingfurther specificity or identification. Even in this limited context, it is unreasonable thatresearchers would wish to \"exacerbate\" or increase the negative effects of damage, andthere is no other word that creates a sentence with the same meaning. \"Stabilize\"implies that the negative effects would simply be controlled, rather than lessened, andlikewise there is no other word that produces a sentence with the same meaning.Thus the correct answer is mitigate (Choice A) and ameliorate (Choice E).",
        "page_num": 96
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 2,
        "questionText": "Some analysts worry about consumers' perception that the electronics industry isalways on the verge of major breakthroughs; that perception could hurt the industryby making consumers reluctant to buy products they believe will soon be              .",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answerOptions": ["incompatible ", "devalued", "obsolete", "ubiquitous", "everywhere", "outmoded"],
        "correctAnswer": [2,5],
        "explanationText": "The blank characterizes products that consumers fear will be superseded in quality as aresult of industry breakthroughs. While \"ubiquitous\" and \"everywhere\" produce sentenceswith the same meaning, they assume an increase in volume or sales that is not necessarilyimplied by innovatory breakthroughs. And while \"devalued\" makes for a coherentsentence, there is no other word that would produce a sentence with the same meaning.Thus the correct answer is obsolete (Choice C) and outmoded (Choice F).",
        "page_num": 96
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 3,
        "questionText": "After people began to make the transition from gathering food to producing food,human societies followed markedly  courses; some adopted herding,others took to tillage, and still others stuck to foraging.",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answerOptions": ["divergent ", "rural", "novel", "unfamiliar", "disparate", "quotidian"],
        "correctAnswer": [0,4],
        "explanationText": "The sentence describes the variable courses of three different societies after thebeginning of a transition, and the blank characterizes the differences among thesecourses. While \"rural\" and \"quotidian\" may describe a common quality of eachcourse, they do not emphasize their variability. And while the words \"novel\" and\"unfamiliar\" are alike in meaning, they do not fit the context, since one of the pathstaken (sticking to foraging) is precisely neither novel nor unfamiliar.Thus the correct answer is divergent (Choice A) and disparate (Choice E).",
        "page_num": 97
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 4,
        "questionText": "In The Simple Soybean, the author is much less restrained in his enthusiasm for thebean's medical efficacy than he is in his technical writings, but he still cautionsagainst treating soy as a  .",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answerOptions": ["staple ", "supplement", "herald", "panacea", "cure-all", "harbinger"],
        "correctAnswer": [3,4],
        "explanationText": "The blank characterizes the medical efficacy or effectiveness of soy. While the words\"herald\" and \"harbinger\" are similar in meaning, they do not characterize medicaleffectiveness as \"panacea\" and \"cure-all\" do. Nor do \"staple\" and \"supplement,\" each ofwhich may refer to a medical regime or a dosage but not to efficacy.Thus the correct answer is panacea (Choice D) and cure-all (Choice E).",
        "page_num": 97
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 5,
        "questionText": "Parkin's characterization of the movement as neoscholastic is too   to beaccepted without further investigation.",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answerOptions": ["cursory ", "detailed", "perfunctory", "biased", "self-evident", "complete"],
        "correctAnswer": [0,2],
        "explanationText": "The blank describes Parkin's characterization as demanding further investigation. If thecharacterization is too \"complete\" or too \"self-evident,\" there is nothing further toinvestigate; if it is too \"detailed\" but not flawed, there is no reason to investigate further.The word \"biased\" does suggest that further investigation is necessary, but there is noother word that produces a sentence alike in meaning.Thus the correct answer is cursory (Choice A) and perfunctory (Choice C).",
        "page_num": 98
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 6,
        "questionText": "A recent study suggests that vitamin E supplements, despite widespread belief intheir  , are no better than sugar pills for delaying the onset of thedegenerative disease.",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answerOptions": ["potential ", "misuse", "popularity", "efficacy", "prevalence", "usefulness"],
        "correctAnswer": [3,5],
        "explanationText": "The sentence suggests that vitamin E supplements are ineffective in deterring the disease,and the use of the word \"despite\" indicates that this ineffectiveness contrasts with howthey are widely viewed. The words that fill the blank, then, must mean the opposite of\"ineffectiveness.\" Among the answer choices, the words that do so are \"efficacy\" and\"usefulness.\" Of the other choices, \"potential\" is tempting, but it does not contrast asdirectly with \"ineffectiveness,\" nor does it have a near synonym among the other answerswith which it could be paired. \"Prevalence\" and \"popularity\" might be initially attractivebecause the passage suggests that these words might describe the use of vitamin Esupplements, but the blank calls for a word that characterizes how they are viewed ratherthan how they are used.Thus the correct answer is efficacy (Choice D) and usefulness (Choice F).",
        "page_num": 98
    }, {
        "questionNumber": 7,
        "questionText": "Despite her relaxed and flexible style, Ms. de la Fressange isbusinesswoman who knows how to market her brand: herself.",
        "difficulty": "Hard",
        "answerOptions": ["a ruthless ", "a creative", "a canny", "an industrious", "a shrewd", "an effective"],
        "correctAnswer": [2,4],
        "explanationText": "The sentence describes Ms. de la Fressange as a businesswoman but none of the wordsbesides \"canny\" and \"shrewd\" provide sentences that are alike in meaning.Thus the correct answer is a canny (Choice C) and a shrewd (Choice E).",
        "page_num": 99
    }]
}